Gianluca Castignani - Curriculum Vitae

Contact
Information

Observatoire de Paris

LERMA

61 avenue de l'Observatoire

75014 Paris, France

E-mail: gianluca.castignani@obspm.fr

webpage: https://sites.google.com/site/gianlucacastignani/home

Role in the PROJECT

Based on my experience on AGNs and distant clusters around radio galaxies I will investigate the role of the environment on star formation in galaxies belonging to the filaments of Virgo using clustering analysis and targeted observations. I will also potentially contribute to the project on high-z galaxy clusters.

Current Position Postdoc

Observatoire de Paris, LERMA 12/2016 - present Laboratoire d'Etudes du Rayonnement et de la Matiére en Astrophysique et Atmosphéres Collège de France 12/2016 - present

• Advisor: Françoise Combes

CNES postdoctoral fellowship

FORMER POSITION Centre National d'Études Spatiales (CNES) postdoctoral fellow

Laboratorie Lagrange, Observatoire de la Côte d'Azur, Nice, France 12/2014 - 11/2016

EDUCATION

PhD in Astrophysics, SISSA, Trieste, Italy	11/2010 - 10/2014
MSc in Physics, University of Pisa, Italy	07/2008 - 10/2010
BSc in Physics, University of Pisa, Italy	09/2005 - 07/2008
Student in Physics, Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa, Italy	10/2005 - 09/2010

Work Experience

Laboratorie Lagrange, Observatoire de la Côte d'Azur, Nice, France 12/2014 - present Euclid consortium, Ground Segment Workpackage Clusters of Galaxies 06/2015 - present Dark Energy Survey (DES), DES-Brasil consortium, LIneA node 10/2016 - present altogether 1 year research period at the **STScI** (Baltimore, USA) 2010 - 2014

Fellowships, HONORS, AND AWARDS

Ph.D. fellowship at SISSA Fondazione Angelo Della Riccia Fellowship (3,500 euro) to work at the STScI Fondazione Angelo Della Riccia Fellowship (1,800 euro) to work at the STScI

04/2014 - 06/2014 03/2013 - 10/201307/2010 - 09/2010

11/2014 - 11/2016 11/2010 - 10/2014

ISSNAF/INAF internship to work at the STScI Scholarship at the Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa, Italy

10/2005 - 09/2010 Competitor at the Italian Olympiads of Physics for high school students, after qualification 2005

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS IN REFEREED JOURNALS

G. Castignani, E. Pian, et al. Multifrequency variability study of the gamma-ray emitting blazar PKS 1510-089, 2017, arXiv:1612.05281, A&A in press • G. Castignani & C. Benoist, A new method to assign galaxy cluster membership using photometric redshifts, 2016, A&A, 595, 111 • G. Castignani & G. De Zotti, AGN torus emission for a homogeneous sample of bright flat spectrum radio quasars, 2015, A&A, 573, 125 • G. Castignani, M. Chiaberge, A. Celotti, & C. Norman, A new method to search for high redshift clusters using photometric redshifts, 2014, ApJ, 792, 113 • G. Castignani, M. Chiaberge, A. Celotti, C. Norman, & G. De Zotti, Cluster candidates around low power radio-galaxies at $z \sim 1-2$ in COSMOS, 2014, ApJ, 792, 114 • G. Castignani, D. Guetta, E. Pian, L. Amati, S. Puccetti, and S. Dichiara, Time delays between Fermi-LAT and GBM light curves of gamma-ray bursts, 2014, A&A, 56, 60 • G. Castignani, F. Haardt, A. Lapi, G. De Zotti, A. Celotti, and L. Danese, Black hole mass estimates for a homogeneous sample of bright flat-spectrum radio quasars, 2013, A&A, 560, 28

Competitor at the Italian Olympiads of Mathematics for high school students, after qualification 2005